This is a wheat bread, a whole wheat bread,
هذا خبز مصنوع من القمح الابيض .. من حبوب القمح الكاملة
and it's made with a new technique
وقد تم صناعته بتقنية جديدة
that I've been playing around with,
قمت باختراعها اثناء لعبي في المطبخ
and developing and writing about which, for lack of a better name,
وتطويري وكتابتي عن وصفات جديدة والتي - التقنية - ندعوها
we call the epoxy method.
تقنية الايبوكسي
And I call it an epoxy method because --
ودعوناها الايبوكسي
it's not very appetizing. I understand that --
والذي اعلم انه اسم لا يثير الشهية كثيرة - انا اتفهم هذا -
but -- but
ولكن .. ولكن
if you think about epoxy, what's epoxy?
ان تسائلتم ما هو الايبوكسي ؟
It's two resins that are, sort of,
انه عبارة عن مادتين مختلفتين
in and of themselves -- neither of which can make glue,
والتي لا يمكن لا واحدة منهما ان تصبح مادة لاصقة بنفسها
but when you put the two together,
ولكن عندما يتم دمجهما معا
something happens. A bond takes place,
يحدث شيء ما .. رابطة ما
and you get this very strong, powerful
لكي تعطي رابط قوي
adhesive.
ومتين جدا
Well, in this technique,
حسناً .. في هذه التقنية الامر كذلك
what I've tried to do is kind of
لقد حاولت
gather all of the knowledge that the bread-baking world,
ان اجمع كل الخبرات في خبز الخبز من حول العالم
the artisan bread-baking community,
ومن مجتمع الخبازين المحترفين
has been trying to accumulate over the last 20 years or so --
الذي حاول التأقلم مع السوق على مدى ال20 عاما الماضية
since we've been engaged in a bread renaissance in America --
منذ بدأت النهضة في صناعة الخبز في الولايات المتحدة الامريكية
and put it together to come up with a method
وخرجت من كلا الطرفين بتقنية جديدة
that would help to take whole-grain breads.
تسمح بصناعة الخبز من حبات القمح الكاملة
And let's face it, everyone's trying to move towards whole grains.
علينا ان نعي .. ان الجميع اليوم يتجه الى صناعة الخبز بحبات القمح الكاملة
We finally, after 40 years of knowing
فنحن منذ 40 عام نعي تماما
that wholegrain was a healthier option,
ان استخدام حبات القمح الكاملة هو اكثر صحية لنا
we're finally getting to the point where we actually are tipping over
وقد استطعنا اخيراً .. والحمد لله .. ان نتجاوز تلك المعلومة وندركها تماما
and attempting to actually eat them.
وان نبدأ فعلا بصناعة واكل ذلك الخبز
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The challenge, though, for a wholegrain baker is,
ان المشكلة الاساسية في خبز الخبز المصنوع من حبات القمح الكاملة
you know, how do you make it taste good?
هي كما تعلمون " الطعم "
Because whole grain -- it's easy with white flour
فمن السهل جدا صناعة خبز " شهي " الطعم بواسطة الطحين الابيض
to make a good-tasting bread. White flour is sweet.
فالطحين الابيض حلو المذاق
It's mainly starch, and starch, when you break it down --
انه في الاساس " نشاء الطبخ " .. فعندما تخبزه
what is starch? It's -- thank you -- sugar, yes.
ماهو نشاء الطبخ ؟ .. انه السكر ؟ ! شكراً لك
So a baker, and a good baker,
ان الخباز الجيد
knows how to pull or draw forth
يعلم تماما كيف يستخرج ويفصل ويميز
the inherent sugar trapped in the starch.
السكر عن النشا في الخلطة
With whole grain bread, you have other obstacles.
ومع حبات القمح الكاملة هناك عقبات أخرى
You've got bran, which is probably the healthiest part of the bread for us,
مثل النخالة .. والتي هي ربما اكثر شيء مفيد في الخبز لنا
or the fiber for us because it is just loaded with fiber,
او انها الالياف .. ولكن النخالة مليئة بها
for the bran is fiber.
اي ان النخالة هي الالياف
It's got germ. Those are the good things,
انها ليست جرثومة ! .. انها شيء جيد
but those aren't the tastiest parts of the wheat.
ولكن مذاقها ليس كذلك
So whole grain breads historically
لذا فقد وصم الخبز المصنوع من حبات القمح الكاملة
have had sort of this onus of being health food breads,
على مدى التاريخ بأنه الخبز الاكثر فائدة صحية لنا
and people don't like to eat,
ولكن الناس لا تستسيغ طعمه
quote, health food. They like to eat healthy and healthily,
وعن الاكل المفيد .. فان الناس تحب ان تأكل المفيد من الطعام
but when we think of something as a health food,
ولكن عندما نتحدث عن الطعام المفيد حقاً ..
we think of it as something we eat out of obligation,
نتحدث عنه وكانه التزام ما يتوجب عليها اكله
not out of passion and love for the flavor.
وليس كطعام نشتهيه .. او نحبه
And ultimately, the challenge of the baker,
والتحدي لكل خباز
the challenge of every culinary student, of every chef,
او طاه .. او متعلم في مدرسة طبخ
is to deliver flavor.
هو ان يضيف النكهة
Flavor is king. Flavor rules.
لان النكهة هي كل شيء
I call it the flavor rule. Flavor rules.
انا اقول دوما .. النكهة هي الحكم في كل شيء
And -- and
و يمكن ..
you can get somebody to eat something that's good for them once,
يمكنك ان تدفع شخص ما لان يأكل طعاما مفيد له مرة واحدة
but they won't eat it again if they don't like it, right?
ولكنه لن يكررها لاحقا ان لم تعجبه نكهتها
So, this is the challenge for this bread.
وهذا هو التحدي للخبازين
We're going to try this at lunch, and
سوف نقوم بتجريب هذا الخبز على الغداء
I'll explain a bit more about it,
وسوف اشرح لكم اكثر عنه
but it's made not only with two types of pre-doughs --
وهو وليس مصنوعٌ فحسب من نوعين من المعجات
this attempt, again, at bringing out flavor
ولكن صنع لجعل النكهة لذيذة جدا
is to make a piece of dough
ولجعل قطعة العجين كذلك علينا ان
the day before that is not leavened.
نضيف للعجين الغير متخمر
It's just dough that is wet.
الماء لترطيبه
It's hydrated dough we call "the soaker" --
وعندما يرطب العجين ندعوه " سوكير "
that helps to start enzyme activity.
وهذا الامر يدفع الانزيميات للعمل
And enzymes are the secret, kind of, ingredient in dough
والانزيميات هي السر .. انها المكون
that brings out flavor.
الذي يجلب النكهة
It starts to release the sugars trapped in the starch.
فهي تعمل على تحرير السكر المرتبط بنشاء الطعام
That's what enzymes are doing.
وهذا هو عمل الانزيمات
And so, if we can release some of those,
اذا .. اذا استطعنا تحرير بعض من جزيئات السكر تلك
they become accessible to us in our palate.
لكي تصبح متوفرة في الطبق الذي نتناوله
They become accessible to the yeast as food.
وتصبح متوفرة للخمائر الموجودة في الطعام كغذاء لها
They become accessible to the oven for caramelization
وتصبح قابلة للطهي بعد تحررها وادخالها الى الفرن
to give us a beautiful crust.
فسنحصل على قطعة خبز جميلة
The other pre-dough
واما العجينة الاخرى
that we make is fermented -- our pre-ferment.
والتي تكون مخمرة في الاساس
And it's made -- it can be a sourdough starter, or what we call a "biga"
والتي تصنع لكي تكون محفزة تخمير .. والتي ندعوها " بيجا "
or any other kind of pre-fermented dough with a little yeast in it,
وهي عجينة مخمرة مسبقا تحوي القليل من الخميرة في داخل مكوناتها
and that starts to develop flavor also.
وهي تبدأ بتحفيز النكهة ايضا
And on day two, we put those two pieces together. That's the epoxy.
وفي اليوم التالي نخلط كلا المادتين .. وهذا هو الايبوكسي
And we're hoping that, sort of, the
ونحن نأمل ان
enzyme piece of dough
الانزيم الموجود في العجينة الاولى
becomes the fuel pack for the leavened piece of dough,
يصبح غذاءا للعجينة المخمرة الثانية
and when we put them together and add the final ingredients,
وعندما نضعهما معا ونضع المكونات النهائية
we can create a bread that does evoke
فنكنون بذلك قد صنعنا خبزاً يحوي
the full potential of flavor trapped in the grain.
فعلا على كل النكهات الموجودة في حبة القمح
That's the challenge. Okay, so, now, what we --
وهذا هو التحدي
in the journey of wheat, let's go back and look at these 12 stages.
في صناعة الخبز يوجد ما يقارب 12 مرحلة
I'm going to go through them very quickly and then revisit them.
وسوف امر عليهم بسرعة ومن ثم سأعيد النظر بهم واتحدث عنهم
Okay, we're going to start with the first stage.
حسنا سوف نبدأ بالمرحلة الاولى
And this is what every student has to begin with.
وهي المرحلة التي يبدأ منها كل طالب سيتعلم الخبز
Everyone who works in the culinary world knows that
كل شخص يعمل في الوظائف المطبخية يعلم هذا الامر
the first stage of cooking is "mise en place,"
ان المرحلة الاولى من اعداد الطعام هي " ميس ان بلاس "
which is just a French way of saying, "get organized."
وهي جملة فرنسية تعني " رتب مكانك "
Everything in its place. First stage.
اي ان يتم وضع كل شي في مكانه .. انها المرحلة الاولى
So in baking we call it scaling -- weighing out the ingredients.
وفي الخبز نحن ندعوها .. القياس .. حيث يتم قياس اوزان كل المكونات
Stage two is mixing. We take the ingredients and we mix them.
المرحلة الثانية هي الخلط .. حيث نعد المكونات ونخلطها
We have to develop the gluten.
لكي نحفز التلاصق فيما بينها
There's no gluten in flour. There's only the potential for gluten.
والطحين لا يوجد فيه مادة " رابطة " ولكنه مؤهل لكي يتم ربطه
Here's another kind of prefiguring of epoxy
اذا هذا نوع آخر من الابوكسي
because we've got glutenin and gliadin,
لاننا نملك هنا " مادة لاصقة " و " مادة سوف تلصق "
neither of which are strong enough to make a good bread.
وكل واحدة منهما لا تترابط فيما بينها جيدا لكي تصنع خبزاً جيداً
But when they get hydrated and they bond to each other,
ولكن عندما يتم ترطيبها تتصل فيما بينها
they create a stronger molecule, a stronger protein we call gluten.
لكي تصنع رابطة قوية .. ندعوها " جلوتين "
And so we, in the mixing process,
وهكذا هذه هي مرحلة الخلط
have to develop the gluten,
التي توفر الترابط بين المواد المكونة للخبز
we have to activate the leaven or the yeast,
والتي نحفز فيها عمل الخميرة .. او الخمائر
and we have to essentially distribute all the ingredients evenly.
وعلينا ان نحرص على خلط وتوزيع المكونات بشكل متساو
Then we get into fermentation, the third stage,
ومن ثم ننتقل الى التخمير .. وهي المرحلة الثالثة
which is really where the flavor develops.
وهي المرحلة التي تتطور فيها النكهة
The yeast comes alive and starts eating the sugars,
حيث تبدا الخمائر بوظيفتها . وتبدأ بالتغذي على السكر الموجود
creating carbon dioxide and alcohol --
لكي تصنع اكسيد الكربون والكحول
essentially it's burping and sweating, which is what bread is.
تحديدا هي تتجشأ وتتعرق .. وهذا هو الخبر
It's yeast burps and sweat.
انه تجشؤ وتعرق الخمائر
And somehow, this is transformed --
وبصورة ما يتحول هذا --
the yeast burps and sweats are later transformed --
هذه الخمائر والسكريات لاحقا
and this is really getting to the heart of what makes bread so special
الى الشيء الاساسي الذي يجعل الخبز شيئاً مميزاً
is that it is a transformational food,
وهذا هو الطعام المتحول
and we're going to explore that in a minute.
وسوف نمر على هذا لاحقا
But then, quickly through the next few stages.
والان لنعد الى المراحل المتبقية
We, after it's fermented and it's developed,
بعد ان يتم تخمير الخبز والسماح به بالنمو
started to develop flavor and character,
لكي يشكل نكهته وشخصيته !
we divide it into smaller units.
تقوم بتقطيعه الى قطع صغيرة
And then we take those units and we shape them. We give them a little pre-shape,
ومن ثم نأخذه هذه القطع الصغيرة ونشكلها .. ونعطيها شكل مبدئي
usually a round or a little torpedo shape, sometimes.
عادة دوائرة صغيرة .. او اشباه منحرفة صغيرة
That's called "rounding."
وتدعى هذه المرحلة " التدوير "
And there's a short rest period. It can be for a few seconds.
وهنالك فترة اراحة صغيرة .. قد تستغرق عدة ثواني ..
It can be for 20 or 30 minutes. We call that resting or benching.
او قد تمتد الى 20-30 دقيقية .. وندعوها نحن فترة الاستراحة
Then we go into final shaping,
ومن ثم ننتقل الى مرحلة تشكيل الشكل النهائي للخبز
"panning" -- which means putting the shaped loaf on a pan.
والتي ندعوها " باننيج " اي وضع الشكل النهائي للعجين على صينية الفرن
This takes a second, but it's a distinctive stage.
وتستغرق بضع ثواني .. ولكنها مرحلة مهمة جدا
It can be in a basket. It can be in a loaf pan, but we pan it.
واحيانا نضع تلك القطع على رغيف اساس .. او في سلة
And then, stage nine.
ومن ثم ننتقل الى المرحلة التاسعة
The fermentation which started at stage three is continuing
ان التخمر الذي بدأ في المرحلة الثالثة مازال مستمرا حتى الآن
through all these other stages. Again, developing more flavor.
عبر هذه المراحل التي تلته .. وهو يشكل النكهة
The final fermentation takes place in stage nine.
والتخمر النهائي .. هو المرحلة التاسعة
We call it "proofing."
ونحن ندعوها " التحقق "
Proofing means to prove that the dough is alive.
اي التحقق من ان العجينة مازالت على قيد الحياة !
And at stage nine we get the dough to the final shape,
وفي المرحلة التاسعة نقوم بوضع العجين بصورته النهائية
and it goes into the oven -- stage 10.
لكي يدخل لاحقا في المرحلة العاشرة الى الفرن
Three transformations take place in the oven.
ويحدث داخل الفرن 3 تحولات
The sugars in the dough caramelize in the crust.
يتم حرق السكر في العجين لكي تعطي لون الكراميل للقشرة
They give us that beautiful brown crust.
وهي المسؤولة عن اللون البني الذهبي للقشرة
Only the crust can caramelize. It's the only place that gets hot enough.
ووحدها القشرة التي تتلون
Inside, the proteins --
لانها الوحيدة المعرضة للحرارة الكافية لذلك، وفي الداخل البروتينات
this gluten -- coagulates.
التي تربط بين العناصر ..تتخثر
When it gets to about 160 degrees,
عندما تصل درجة الحرارة الى 160 درجة
the proteins all line up and they create structure,
فتتجمع البروتينات لكي تعطي شكل الخبز
the gluten structure --
اي هيكل الخبز
what ultimately we will call the crumb of the bread.
والذي هو الشكل الذي يخرج فيه الخبز
And the starches, when they reach about 180 degrees,
ومن ثم النشا وعندما تصل درجة الحرارة الى 180
gelatinize.
يتميه
And gelatinization is yet another
والتميه هي عملية
oven transformation.
تحول اخرى تحدث في الفرن
Coagulation, caramelization and gelatinization --
والتي هي حرق السكر . التميه .. الترابط
when the starch is thick and they absorb all the moisture that's around them,
عندما يصبح النشا سميكاً .. ويكون قد امتص كل الرطوبة من حوله
they -- they kind of swell, and then they burst.
فانه ينتفخ .. ومن ثم يتصلب
And they burst, and they spill their guts into the bread.
ومن ثم يدفع بجزئياته التي تحطمت بفعل الحرارة الى مكونات الخبز
So basically now we're eating yeast sweats --
اي ان النكهة تحديدا تأتي من سكريات الخمائر
sweat, burps and starch guts.
التي تخرجها بسبب تفاعلاتها وتحولاتها
Again, transformed in stage 10 in the oven
اذا ان الذي دخل في المرحلة العاشرة الى الفرن
because what went into the oven as dough
لأن ما دخل إلى الفرن كعجين
comes out in stage 11 as bread.
هو ذاته الذي سيخرج من المرحلة ال11 كخبز
And stage 11, we call it cooling --
والمرحلة ال11 هي التبريد
because we never really eat the bread right away.
لاننا لا نأكل الخبز حالما يخرج من الفرن
There's a little carry-over baking.
فهناك عناية خاصة به تجري بعد خروجه من الفرن
The proteins have to set up, strengthen and firm up.
لكي تقوى الروابط بين البروتينات .. ويثبت تشكلها النهائي
And then we have stage 12, which the textbooks call "packaging,"
ومن ثم نصل الى المرحلة الثانية عشر والتي هي التغليف
but my students call "eating."
ولكن طلابي يدعونها " الاكل "
And so, we're going to be on our own journey today from wheat to eat,
اذا رحلتنا اليوم اخذتكم من القمح الى الاكل
and in a few minutes we will try this,
وخلال بضع دقائق سوف نجرب هذه
and see if we have succeeded
لنرى ان كنا قد نجحنا
in fulfilling this baker's mission of pulling out flavor.
في استخراج النكهة والتي هي مهمة الخباز في الاساس
But I want to go back now and revisit these steps,
ولكن اريد ان اعود وان اقف عند بضع مراحل
and talk about it from the standpoint of transformation,
وان اتحدث عن وجهة نظري في التحولات التي جرت
because I really believe that
لانني اظن وأؤمن
all things can be understood --
ان كل شيء يمكن فهمه
and this is not my own idea. This goes back to the Scholastics and to the Ancients --
وهذه ليست فكرتي في الاساس . .بل تعود الى شولاستيس .. والى الاسلاف
that all things can be understood on four levels:
ويقولون . .ان كل شيء يمكن فهمه على 4 مراحل
the literal, the metaphoric or poetic level,
الادبية.. والرمزية أو الشعرية
the political or ethical level.
والسياسية . .والاخلاقية
And ultimately, the mystical or sometimes called the "anagogical" level.
او الذي يمكن ان ندعوه " الخرافية .. او الاثنية "
It's hard to get to those levels unless you go through the literal.
ومن الصعب جدا فهم هذه المراحل ان لم نمر بمرحلة الادب
In fact, Dante says you can't understand the three deeper levels
لقد قال " دانتي " لا يمكننا ان نستوعب المراحل الثلاث
unless you first understand the literal level,
دون ان نعي جيداً المفهوم الادبي
so that's why we're talking literally about bread.
اذا سوف نتحدث عن المفهوم الادبي للخبز
But let's kind of look at these stages again
اذا لنعد النظر على تلك المراحل مرة اخرى
from the standpoint of connections to possibly a deeper level --
منذ البداية ..الى الترابط .. الى التفاعلات التي تحدث في الاعماق
all in my quest for answering the question,
بهدف الاجابة على السؤال
"What is it about bread that's so special?"
الذي يقول " ماهو الشيء المميز في الخبز ؟ "
And fulfilling this mission of evoking the full potential of flavor.
ولكي احاول فهم وظيفتي لاتمام مهمة استنباط النكهة الممكنة في الخبز
Because what happens is,
ان الذي يحدث هو
bread begins as wheat or any other grain.
ان الخبز يبدا من القمح
But what's wheat? Wheat is a grass
ولكن ماهو القمح .. انه السنابل
that grows in the field.
التي تنمو في الحقول
And, like all grasses, at a certain point it puts out seeds.
وكما بقية النباتات في مرحلة ما يتوجب عليها بذر البذور
And we harvest those seeds, and those are the wheat kernels.
ولكننا نحصد هذه البذور .. والتي هي القمح
Now, in order to harvest it -- I mean, what's harvesting?
ولكي نحصدها .. اعني .. ما هو الحصد
It's just a euphemism for killing, right?
انه عملية قتل .. اليس كذلك ؟
I mean, that's what's harvest -- we say we harvest the pig, you know?
هذا هو الحصد .. اليس كذلك .. فعندما نقول اننا نحصد الخنزير/الخروف
Yes, we slaughter, you know. Yes, that's life.
يعني اننا نذبحه
We harvest the wheat,
نحن اذا نحصد القمح
and in harvesting it, we kill it.
وعندما نحصده .. فنحن نقتله
Now, wheat is alive,
ان القمح كائن حي !
and as we harvest it, it gives up its seeds.
وعندما نحصده نحن .. ونأخذ بذوره
Now, at least with seeds we have the potential for future life.
تلك البذور التي تهدف الى اعادة دورة الحياة في المستقبل
We can plant those in the ground.
والتي يمكننا زرعها في الارض
And we save some of those for the next generation.
والتي نخبأ بعضاً منها للاجيال القادمة
But most of those seeds get crushed
ولكن معظم تلك البذور تتطحن
and turned into flour.
وتحول الى قمح
And at that point, the wheat has suffered the ultimate indignity.
وبهذه النقطة يكون القمح قد تعرض لاهانة كبيرة !
It's not only been killed,
فهو لم يقتل فحسب
but it's been denied any potential for creating future life.
بل تم منعه من اتمام دورة حياته في المستقبل
So we turn it into flour.
حسناً .. نحن نحول القمح الى طحين
So as I said, I think bread is a transformational food.
وكما قلت مسبقا.. ان الخبز هو طعام متحول
The first transformation -- and, by the way,
اول تحول يتعرض له
the definition of transformation for me is
بالمناسبة كلمة تحول تعني لي
a radical change from one thing into something else.
شيء جذري يتغير
O.K.? Radical, not subtle.
جذري .. حسناً
Not like hot water made cold,
ليس كتحول الماء الساخن الى البارد
or cold water turned hot,
او البارد الى ساخن
but water boiled off and becoming steam.
ولكن كتحول الماء الساخن الى بخار
That's a transformation, two different things.
هذا هو التحول .. تغير جذري بين حالتين
Well, in this case, the first transformation
وفي هذه الحالة.. التحول الاول هو
is alive to dead.
التحول من الحياة الى الموت !
I'd call that radical.
ان هذا لهو تحول جذري
So, we've got now this flour.
حسنا نحن نملك الان الطحين
And what do we do? We add some water.
فماذا نفعل ؟ .. نضع القليل من الماء
In stage one, we weigh it.
في المرحلة الاولى نحن . .نزن الطحين
In stage two, we add water and salt to it, mix it together,
وفي المرحلة الثانية نضع الماء والملح .. ونخلطهم معاً
and we create something that we call "clay."
ومن ثم نصنع ما يسمى " الغضار " - اساس العجينة
It's like clay.
لانها تشبه الغضار
And we infuse that clay
ومن ثم نحقن ذلك الغضار
with an ingredient that we call "leaven."
بالمكونات الاخرى مثل الخميرة
In this case, it's yeast, but yeast is leaven. What does leaven mean?
وفي هذه الحالة .. الخمائر الموجودة في الخميرة .. تقوم بعملها .. وما هو ؟
Leaven comes from the root word that means enliven --
ان كلمة الخمائر جائت من جذر كلمة " مفعم بالحياة "
to vivify, to bring to life.
اي لكي ينعش .. او لكي يعيد الى الحياة
By the way, what's the Hebrew word for clay? Adam.
بالمناسبة ان كلمة غضار بالعبرية هي " آدم "
You see, the baker, in this moment,
كما ترون في هذه الحالة الخباز
has become, in a sense,
قد اصبح على نحو ما
sort of, the God of his dough, you know, and his dough, well,
كخالق لعجينته .. كما تعلمون .. انها عجينته
while it's not an intelligent life form, is now alive.
رغم انها ليست صورة متقدمة من الحياة .. ولكنها حياة
And we know it's alive because in stage three,
ونحن نعلم انها على قيد الحياة لانه في المرحلة الثالثة
it grows. Growth is the proof of life.
تنمو .. النمو دليل على الحياة
And while it's growing, all these
وعندما تنمو .. كل
literal transformations are taking place.
تلك التحولات الادبية تحدث
Enzymes are breaking forth sugars.
حيث تحطم الانزيمات روابط السكر
Yeast is eating sugar and
وتأكل الخمائر السكر
turning it into carbon dioxide and alcohol.
ومن ثم تحوله الى اكسيد الكربون والكحول
Bacteria is in there, eating the same sugars,
والبكتريا الموجودة هناك تأكل بعض السكر ايضا
turning them into acids.
لتحولها الى بعض من الاحماض
In other words, personality and character's being developed in this dough
بمعنى آخر .. ان الشخصية والقوام ينموان في العجينة
under the watchful gaze of the baker.
تحت اشراف الخباز بنفسه
And the baker's choices all along the way
لان خيارات الخباز على مدى تلك المراحل
determine the outcome of the product.
هي التي ستحدد نوعية المنتج الذي سيخرج لاحقاً
A subtle change in temperature -- a subtle change in time --
مهما كان بسيطا.. سواء كان تغيرا بسيطا في الحرارة .. او الوقت
it's all about a balancing act between time, temperature
والامر كله متعلق بالتوازن بين الحرارة والوقت
and ingredients. That's the art of baking.
وبين المكونات .. انه فن .. فن الخبز
So all these things are determined by the baker,
اذا كل تلك المعطيات تحدد من قبل الخباز
and the bread goes through some stages, and characters develop.
بينما يمر الخبز بعدة مراحل تشكل شخصيته وطبيعته
And then we divide it, and this one big piece of dough
ومن ثم يتم تقطيعه .. الى قطعة عجيب كبيرة
is divided into smaller units, and each of those units
ومن ثم تقطع الى قطع اصغر
are given shape by the baker.
وتعطى الشكل النهائي
And as they're shaped, they're raised again,
وعندما يتم تشكيلها .. تنمو مرة اخرى
all along proving that they're alive,
كدليل اخر انها على قيد الحياة
and developing character.
وتشكل القطع الصغيرة شخصيتها الخاصة بها
And at stage 10, we take it to the oven.
وعند المرحلة ال10 عندما تؤخذ الى فرن
It's still dough. Nobody eats bread dough --
تكون مازلت العجين .. عجيناً .. ولا احد يأكل عجين الخبز
a few people do, I think, but not too many.
ربما البعض يفعل ذلك .. ولكن ليس الكثير
I've met some dough eaters, but --
لقد قابلت بعضاً منهم ..
it's not the staff of life, right? Bread is the staff of life.
ولكن هذا ليس امرا صحي . او جيد .. اليس كذلك ؟ ان الخبز يشبه الحياة !
But dough is what we're working with,
ان العجين هي التي نعمل بها
and we take that dough to the oven,
وهي التي يتم أخذها الى الفرن
and it goes into the oven. As soon as the interior temperature of that dough
وعندما تدخل الى الفرن .. وعندما تتجاوز الحرارة الداخلية للعجين
crosses the threshold of 140 degrees,
مستوى 140 درجة مئوية
it passes what we call the "thermal death point."
تقطع ما نسمية " الحرارة المميتة "
Students love that TDP. They think it's the name of a video game.
ان الطلاب يحبون هذا الاسم .. انهم يظنون انه اسم لعبة فيديو
But it's the thermal death point -- all life ceases there.
وعند نقطة الحرارة المميتة هذه تموت كل اشكال الحياة
The yeast, whose mission it has been up till now to raise the dough,
مثل الخمائر والتي كانت تدفع العجين الى النمو
to enliven it, to vivify it,
والى التطور .. وهي التي اعادة الحياة اليها
in order to complete its mission,
ولكي تكمل مهمتها
which is also to turn this dough into bread,
والتي هي تحويل العجين الى خبز
has to give up its life.
عليها ان تضحي بحياتها !
So you see the symbolism at work? It's starting to come forth a little bit, you know.
اريتم الرمزية في صناعة الخبز ؟ انها تتوضح الان اليس كذلك ؟
It's starting to make sense to me --
لقد بدا الامر يصبح منطقياً
what goes in is dough,
ما يدخل الى الفرن هو العجين
what comes out is bread --
وما يخرج هو الخبز
or it goes in alive,
ما يدخل على قيد الحياة
comes out dead.
يخرج ميتا
Third transformation. First transformation, alive to dead.
التحول الثالث .. هو التحول الاول .. من الحياة الى الموت
Second transformation, dead brought back to life.
التحول الثاني .. هو التحول من الموت الى الحياة
Third transformation, alive to dead --
الثالث .. من الحياة الى الموت
but dough to bread.
العجين الى الخبز
Or another analogy would be,
كعلم الاحياء المليء بالامثلة
a caterpillar has been turned into a butterfly.
مثل تحول اليرقة الى فراشة
And it's what comes out of the oven
ان ما يخرج من الفرن
that is what we call the staff of life.
هو نتاج الحياة
This is the product
هو المنتج
that
الذي
everyone in the world eats, that is so difficult to give up.
يأكله جميع الاشخاص حول العالم .. والذي لا يمكن التخلي عنه
It's so
انه
deeply embedded in our psyches that
يتجذر عميقا في تراثنا وافكارنا
bread is used as a symbol for life.
ان الخبز بالنسبة لنا .. رمزٌ للحياة
It's used as a symbol for transformation.
وهو رمز للتحول !
And so, as we get to stage 12 and we partake of that,
وعندما يصل الى المرحلة ال12 ونحن نتشارك في هذا
again completing the life cycle,
لكي نكمل دورة الحياة
you know, we have a chance to essentially ingest that --
كما تعلمون اننا نهضم هذا الطعام
it nurtures us, and we continue to carry on
وهو يغذينا .. لكي نستمر بالحياة
and have opportunities to ponder
ولكي نفكر بالقيام
things like this.
باشياء مثل هذه
So this is what I've learned from bread.
اذا ما تعلمته من الخبز
This is what bread has taught me in my journey.
هذا هو ما عملني اياه الخبز خلال رحلتي معه
And what we're going to attempt to do
والذي سنحاول القيام به هنا
with this bread here, again,
مع قطعة الخبز هذه
is to use, in addition to everything we talked about,
هو اكله ! . .بالاضافة لكل ما تحدثنا عنه
this bread we're going to call "spent grain bread"
هذا الخبز ندعوه خبز " الحبوب المستخدمة "
because, as you know, bread-making is very similar to beer-making.
لانه كما تعلمون صناعة الخبز تشبه صناعة شراب الشعير/النبيذ
Beer is basically liquid bread,
ان شراب الشعير هو خبز سائل !
or bread is solid beer.
او ان الخبز هو شراب الشعير متصلب
And --
و
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
they -- they're invented around the same time. I think beer came first.
لقد تم اختراعهما في نفس الوقت .. اعتقد ان شراب الشعير تم اختراعه اولا
And the Egyptian who was tending the beer fell asleep
ومن ثم نام المصريون بعد ان شربوا الشعير
in the hot, Egyptian sun, and it turned into bread.
في حرارة مصر .. فتحول شراب الشعير الى خبز
But we've got this bread,
لكي نحصل نحن على الخبز في النهاية
and what I did here is to try to, again,
وما قمت به هنا مرة اخرى
evoke even more flavor from this grain,
هو ان احفز خروج النكهة من القمح
was we've added into it the spent grain from beer-making.
وقد استفدنا من تقنية " الحبوب المستخدمة " التي تستخدم في صناعة شراب الشعير
And if you make this bread, you can use any kind of spent grain from any type of beer.
واذا اردت ان تصنع هذا الخبز .. فيمكنك ان تستخدم اي نوع كان من " الحبوب المستخدمة " في صناعة شراب الشعير
I like dark spent grain. Today we're using a light spent grain
انا احب " الحبوب المستخدمة " غامقة اللون .. وهنا استخدمنا فاتحة اللون
that's actually from, like, some kind of a lager of some sort --
وهذه هي شاكلة .. تشبه خلطة كبيرة
a light lager or an ale -- that is wheat and barley that's been toasted.
من حبوب قمح ونخالة تم تحميصها
In other words, the beer-maker knows also how to evoke flavor from the grains
بمعنى آخر .. صانعوا شراب الشعير يعرفون تماما كيفية استخراج النكهة من حبوب القمح
by using sprouting and malting and roasting.
باستخدام التخمير والتحميص للشعير
We're going to take some of that, and put it into the bread.
وسوف نستعين بهذا وسوف نضيف كل ذاك الى صناعة الخبز
So now we not only have a high-fiber bread,
فنحن اليوم لا نملك فحسب خبز يحوي العديد من الالياف
but now fiber on top of fiber.
بل نملك ايضا اليافا مضافة الى الالياف القمحية في الاساس
And so this is, again, hopefully
ومرة اخرى انه ليس
not only a healthy bread,
فحسب خبز صحي
but a bread that you will enjoy.
بل هو خبز يمكنك الاستمتاع باكله
So, if I, kind of, break this bread,
سوف اقسم هذا الخبز
maybe we can share this now a little bit here.
ربما يمكننا تذوقه الان
We'll start a little piece here,
وسوف اعطي هنا هذه القطعة
and I'm going to take a little piece here --
وسوف اعطي لهنا هذه القطعة
I think I'd better taste it myself before you have it at lunch.
واريد ان اتذوق انا بنفسي ايضا هذا الخبز .. قبل الغداء
I'll leave you
وسوف اترككم
with what I call the baker's blessing.
مع ما اسميه " بركة الخباز "
May your crust be crisp,
لتكن قشرة خبزكم ذهبية
and your bread always rise.
ولينمو خبزكم دوما بصورة كافية
Thank you.
شكراً